Welcome back to the channel or hi if
you're new here. I'm Elise and today
we're going to be learning how to
crochet these super quick and easy
amarroomi hearts. These are so quick and
they are perfect if you have some yarn
scraps to use up. These are beginner
friendly, so I will be going over all of
the stitches with you as we use them.
And you can make these in really any
size that you like by changing the yarn
weight and hook size that you use. For
my hearts here, I'm going to be using
some worsted weight for acrylic yarn and
a 4mm hook, but like I said, you can use
any yarn and corresponding hook size to
change the size of your heart.
You're also going to need a pair of
scissors and some filling for the middle
of your heart. If you don't have
polyfill, that is perfectly fine. You
can just use some yarn scraps. That's
what I did.
And once we have everything, we are
ready to go ahead and get started.
Okay. Okay, to get started on our heart,
the first thing we have to do is make a
slip knot. To make a slip knot, we're
going to wrap the yarn around two of our
fingers and across just like this. Then
I'm pinching that yarn tail with my
thumb so it doesn't come undone. Then
I'm taking my pointer finger on my other
hand and I'm putting it under that first
strand of yarn and over the second, just
like that. Then I'm just flipping that
second strand of yarn up and pulling it
tight.
Let's do that together one more time.
Wrap the yarn around two of your fingers
and across. Pinch the yarn tail with
your thumb. Take your finger on your
other hand and put it under the first
strand of yarn and over the second. Then
flip that second strand of yarn up and
pull it tight to make your slip knot.
Now that we have our slip knot, we can
go ahead and put our hook into that
loop. Pull on this yarn tail to go ahead
and close that loop down around the
hook. Just like that.
And now we can make our chain.
To make a chain, all you have to do is
grab that yarn with the hook and pull it
right through that loop. Again, grab the
yarn and pull it right through that loop
on the hook. Now, we're going to make
six single crochets into the first chain
that we made right there. So, go back
into that very first chain that you
made. Just like that. And to make a
single crochet, we're going to yarn over
and pull up a loop so that we have two
loops on our hook.
Then we will yarn over and pull through
both of those loops on the hook. And
there's our first single crochet.
Again, go back into that same chain.
Yarn over and pull up a loop. So that
you have two loops on your hook. Yarn
over and pull through both of those
loops on the hook. And there's your
second single crochet.
So let's go ahead and do that four more
times for a total of six single
crochets.
Just like that. Then I'm going to pull
on this yarn tail at the back to go
ahead and close up that circle a little
bit.
And then we're going to finish round one
by making a slip stitch into the first
single crochet that we made. So go ahead
and find that very first single crochet
that you made at the beginning of the
round.
Go under both of those loops at the top
of the stitch. And to make a slip
stitch, we're just going to yarn over
and pull up a loop. And then pull that
right through the loop on our hook to
make a slip stitch.
Okay, so we are all done with round one.
Let's go ahead and start on round two.
We're always going to start by chaining
one. That will not count as a stitch.
And now for round two, we're going to
make two single crochets into every
stitch all the way around. And we're
going to start right here into this very
first stitch. That is the same stitch
that you made your slip stitch into.
And like I said, we're going to make two
single crochets into every stitch. So
there is my first single crochet. I'm
going back into that same stitch
and making a second single crochet
again. and going into the next stitch.
Always make sure you're going under both
of those loops at the top of every
stitch.
And there's one
and two single crochets.
So go ahead and keep making two single
crochets into every stitch all the way
around. And you should end round two
with 12 single crochets in total.
Okay, I'm at the end of round two. We're
going to go ahead and finish up round
two by making a slip stitch into the top
of that first single crochet that we
made. So, go ahead and find that first
single crochet
and make your slip stitch.
That completes round two. Let's go ahead
and start on round three. So, chain one.
And now for round three, we're only
going to put one single crochet into
every stitch all the way around. Again,
we're going to start right here into
this very first stitch. That's the same
stitch that we made our slip stitch
into.
And make one single crochet.
One single crochet into the next stitch.
One single crochet into the following
stitch.
And just keep repeating that all the way
around. And you should end round three
again with 12 stitches in total.
Okay, so that completes round three. And
you can see that it's starting to curl
up a little bit. That is exactly what we
want. Okay, so this is going to be the
top of the first half of our heart. So
we're going to go ahead and tie off. set
this aside and do the exact same thing
that we just did. So, let's go ahead and
chain one,
cut the yarn,
pull that right up through that chain
that you made, and pull it tight.
And I'm just going to pull that yarn
tail to the back so it doesn't get in
the way.
Okay, so there's the first piece of our
heart. Go ahead and do the exact same
thing through round three, but this time
I don't want you to tie off. So, go
ahead and rewind the video if you need
to, but we want a second piece identical
to this first one. Except in the second
one, we are not going to tie off. So, go
ahead and do that and I'll meet you
right back here.
Okay. So, I've got both of my pieces
here, and we're going to go ahead and
continue on first by attaching them
together. So, without chaining one on
the piece that I have not tied off on,
I'm going to go ahead and go into this
first piece that I made, you can go into
any stitch
along that last row that we made. Make
sure you go under both of those loops,
and we're just going to start making our
single crochets. So, I'm going into that
stitch on that first piece
and making a single crochet. Okay. So,
now those two pieces are attached
together. So, what we're going to do now
is we're just going to keep making our
single crochets
all the way around this first piece that
we made all the way around. You should
have 12 single crochets in total. As you
go around this first piece,
just making one single crochet into
every stitch
all the way around.
Okay. So, once you've worked all the way
around that first piece there, and
you've made all 12 of your single
crochets, we're going to go ahead and
pick back up on this second piece here.
So go right into that first stitch and
make your next single crochet.
Just like that. And now we're going to
do the same thing on the second piece.
So we're going to make one single
crochet all the way around the second
piece again for a total of 12 single
crochets.
So you should end this next row working
around both pieces with 24 single
crochets in total.
Okay. So, once you've worked all the way
around and you have all 24 of your
single crochets around both of those
pieces, we're going to go ahead and
finish the round by making a slip
stitch. And we're going to go right into
that first stitch that we made right
there in the middle.
Just like that.
And we'll start the next round by
chaining one.
And this next round, I'm going to call
round five, is going to be our first
decreasing round. So in round five,
we're going to start off by making four
single crochets. One in each of the next
four stitches.
We'll start right here into that same
stitch that we made our slip stitch
into. So there's one,
2,
3,
and four.
We're going to make our first decrease.
To do that, we're going to do a single
crochet two together.
And to do that, we're going to start our
first single crochet into that next
stitch, but don't finish it.
Then I'm going into the following
stitch, yarning over, and pulling up a
loop. so that I have three loops on my
hook. Then I'm yarning over and pulling
through all three of those loops on the
hook. And that is my decrease or my
single crochet two together.
Now we're going to make our next four
single crochets.
So there's one
and four.
And now we'll make our next decrease.
So start your next single crochet into
that next stitch, but don't finish it.
Then go into the following stitch. Yarn
over and pull up a loop. Yarn over and
pull through all three of those loops on
the hook. And there is your next
decrease.
Make your next four single crochets.
So there's one,
2,
3,
and four.
Make your next decrease.
And then your next four single crochets.
There's one,
2,
3,
and four. And then our very last
decrease should fall on the very last
two stitches of the round. So if your
decrease is not landing on the very last
two stitches, something has gone wrong.
Go ahead and rewind the video.
But we're going to go ahead and make our
last decrease along those last two
stitches.
Just like that. We'll finish the round
by making our slip stitch into that
first single crochet that we made at the
beginning of the round.
And we're ready to start on round six.
So chain one. And now this time, instead
of four single crochets between our
decreases, we should have three single
crochets between each one of our
decreases.
So go ahead and make three single
crochets starting in that very first
stitch, the same stitch that we made our
slip stitch into. So there's one,
2,
and three.
Then we'll make our decrease
our next three single crochets. So
there's one,
two,
and three.
Our next decrease.
Then our next three single crochets.
There's one,
two,
and three.
Our next decrease.
Our
next three single crochets.
And finally, our last decrease again
should fall across the last two stitches
of the round.
So go ahead and make your last decrease
along those last two stitches.
Finish round six by making your slip
stitch into that very first single
crochet that you made at the beginning
of the round.
And that completes round six.
Let's start round seven by chaining one.
And for round seven, instead of three
single crochets between our decreases,
we're going to have two.
So single crochet two starting in that
very first stitch.
There's one and two. And then we'll make
our first decrease.
Single crochet two.
There's one and two.
And then make your next decrease.
Single crochet two
and make your next decrease
again. Single crochet two.
And your last decrease should fall
across the last two stitches.
Finish up round seven by making your
slip stitch into that first single
crochet that you made.
Okay, so at this point I'm going to go
ahead and add some filling to my heart
before that hole gets too small. And
like I said at the beginning of the
video, you can either use some yarn
scraps or some polyfill, whatever you
have. So I'm going to go grab that and
we will add our filling and then finish
up our heart.
Okay, I've added my yarn scraps into my
heart as you can see.
So, we're going to go ahead and work on
the next round. Start off by chaining
one.
And for this next round, we're going to
be making our decrease every other
stitch. So, we'll make one single
crochet
and then our decrease.
one single crochet
One single crochet and our next
decrease.
One single crochet
and then our last decrease. Again, that
last decrease should fall across those
last two stitches.
Make your slip stitch into that first
single crochet that you made at the
beginning of the round.
Okay, and we only have one more round to
go. So, let's chain one.
And as you may have guessed, for this
very last round, we're going to be
making decreases all the way around. You
should end this round with four
decreases in total.
So there's my first decrease,
my second decrease,
my third decrease,
and my fourth and final decrease.
It's a little bit tricky here at the
end. Finish up that last round by making
your slip stitch into that very first
decrease that you made.
And that completes our heart. So, we're
going to go ahead and finish it off by
chaining one.
Cut your yarn.
Pull that right up through that chain
that you made and pull it tight.
And then we can weave it in by pulling
it down through the center of the point
of our heart.
Okay, and you are all done with your
heart. Thank you so much for watching. I
really hope that you enjoyed the
tutorial. Go ahead and let me know in
the comments how your heart turned out
and what you'd like to see next.
Subscribe if you're not already. It's
the easiest way you can help support the
channel and my work for free and it
really helps me out.
And with all that being said, I will see
you in the next one.